

#### **Juan Camilo Martinez Villada**

# **Personal Details** 3128996127 martinezvilada@hotmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/juan-camilo-martinez-villada-30b982a1/

## **Career Summary**

I am system engineer that I had the opportunity to take part at project international currency banking with Mizuho bank in city Mexico I worked with technologies as Spring boot (mvc, data, security, Thymeleaf), manages dependencies maven and Oracle PL/SQL and documentation API res with swagger In my work experience I have worked with implementation micro-services architecture and SOA on banking projects with technologies like Java 8, Spring Framework, ORM hibernate under agile methodologies like scrum.

# **Summary of Qualifications**

Skills:

• Java 1.7, 1.8, 11

- Spring Framework
- Hibernate
- Versioning Git/SVN

- PL/SQL
- JavaScript
- Thymeleaf
- Bootstrap
- Struts JSF
- Swagger 2 Maven Tomcat/We
  - loogic/GCP
  - OSB oracle
  - API rest JAX-RX
  - SOLID

- Mockito/Junit
- Firebase
- Scrum
- JIRA
- Confluence

Languages:

Spanish (native speaker)

English (B1+)

#### **Career History**

## **SOPHOS BANKING SOLUTIONS, Medellin, Colombia**

Implementation Consultant

- had the opportunity to take part in currency international project, banking I worked with Mizuho bank in Mexico and finished website codification for the customer Mizuho in Mexico on minor time requested.
- I led and designed the solution for new Blotter at customer Mizuho in Mexico.
- I was recognized by my achievements testing reports for customer Banismo.

# Universidad EAFIT, Medellin, Colombia

Mar. 2018 - Oct. 2019

Agu. 2016 - Feb. 2018

System Analyst

- Design and develop architectures, configurations and components to implement new features.
- I worked and designed, the solutions for decoupling fifty-four application by new suit core (People Software Campus Solutions).
- I led a little team "three developers" We designed for decouple fifty-four applications.

## **Globant, Medellin, Colombia**

Oct. 2019 - Nov. 2021

Java Developer Analyst Sr

- Made software archaeology for integration project
- Design and develop configurations and components to implement new features that will replace the current integration.
- Attend daily meetings to report status and present demos about new features.
- Created new documentation in the wiki confluence.

# **EPAM Anywhere, Medellin, Colombia**

Senior Software Engineer

- Building and modifying the software to support the retail allocation project
- Watch the services in event-driven architecture to ensure the healthy around topics and consumers

Dec. 2021 – Present

- Design and develop configurations and components to implement new features that will replace the legacy implementation.
- Attend daily stand-ups to report status and present demos about new features.
- Created new documentation in the wiki confluence.

### Education

Institucion Universitaria de Envigado, Envigado, Colombia BS, Systems Engineering OR BS, Computer Science	Jan. 2013 – Dec. 2017
<b>Institucion Universitaria de Envigado</b> , Medellín, Colombia CCNA Routing and Switching: Connecting Networks	Jul. 2014 – Nov. 2014
Institucion Universitaria de Envigado, Medellín, Colombia CCNA Routing and Switching: Scaling Networks	Feb. 2015 – May. 2015
<b>Institucion Universitaria de Envigado</b> , Medellín, Colombia CCNA Routing and Switching: Essentials	Jul. 2015 – Nov. 2015
<b>Institucion Universitaria de Envigado</b> , Medellín, Colombia CCNA Routing and Switching: Introduction to Networks	Feb. 2016 – May. 2016